good evening ladies and gentlemen and a
very warm welcome to icici lombard
general insurance company limited
q1 fy23 conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav
md and ceo of the company
mr gopal balachandran cfo and cro
mr sanjeev mantri executive director
and mr alok agarwal
director
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication
of any future performance as future
involves risk
and uncertainties which could cause
results to differ materially from the
current views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing start and zero on
your touchstone phone please note that
this conference is being recorded
i now hand the conference order mr bharg
of dasgupta md and ceo icici lombard
general insurance limited thank you and
over to you sir
uh thank you needles uh and good evening
to each one of you thank you for joining
the our earnings conference call for q1
fi 23.
i will give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that
we've witnessed in the last few months
post this our cfo mr gopal bala children
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter ended june
30 2022.
during the quarter the indian economy
continued to steadily grow towards the
pre-pandemic levels with broad-based
improvement across consumption
investment credit growth of banking
sector etc
in spite of the headwinds of inflation
geopolitical tension and surprising
disruptions with improved rural and
strong urban demand the optimism towards
india's economic recovery remains intact
amidst this the gi industry performed
reasonably well primarily driven by
segments such as health insurance and
motor insurance
as for the data published by cm the new
vehicle sales witnessed moderate growth
for private car segment amidst continued
supply game constraints
the commercial vehicle segment grew
robustly supported by underlying demand
while the two-wheeler segment continued
to remain slow compared to pre-pandemic
levels
health insurance in line with the
expectations
contributed to the overall industry
growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
sync with the current market environment
resultantly the gi industry delivered a
gpi growth of 23 for q1 fi 2023
as for public disclosures the combined
ratio of the industry was 118.1 in fy 20
excluding one company which is yet to
disclose the q4 results
as compared to 112.2 in fbi 2021
we give this data with a one quarter lag
because that's when we get the full
information
moving to regulatory updates the
government of india where the ministry
of road transport and highways in
consultation with the authority on may
25 2022 published revision and base
premium for motor third party insurance
for various classes of
vehicles effective from june 1
2 0 to 2.
the rate hike is expected to be
marginally positive however the rise is
not considered with the loss experience
and the inflation that the industry has
been has envisaged in the segment
and with the current need to increase
insurance penetration in the country the
authority has recently announced several
measures for the benefit of
policyholders and towards ensuring ease
of doing business for insurers
this includes reducing compliance burden
on regulated entities by rationalizing
regulatory framework
forming committees working committees
towards distribution reforms finance and
solvency based related provisions
product governance regulatory and
statutory reforms and review of data and
technology framework and organizing
bi-monthly interactive sessions with the
insurance for the suggestions for
increasing insurance penetration
subsequently on june 1 uh 2022 the
authority prescribed the user fine
procedure for all health insurance
products and almost all generations
products by moving from the current
regime requiring prior approval for
launching retail products to a regime
where products could be launched without
prior approval
on july 14 2022 user file was also
extended for agriculture and allied
services
on july 5 2022 the authority permitted
general insurance companies to introduce
the following take enable concepts for
motor drone damage uh as as an add-on to
basic policy
uh one pay as you drive to pay how you
drive
three floater policy for vehicles
belonging to the same individual owner
for two wheelers and private cars
the company had launched similar
products under the regulatory sandbox
initiative in 2020 wherein there was a
limitation of 50 lakh of premium or 10
000 policy policies whichever is
achieved earlier
in line with the above regulatory change
the company has launched its motor
floater add-on cover recently it
provides convenience to customers of
having one policy document one renewal
date and one premium at lower cost
moving to business impact for us in q1
2023 the company grew by 24.9 percent as
compared to the industry growth of 21.7
excluding crop and marcel
coming to the both for key segments
during the quarter for motor the company
grew in line with the industry and has
maintained its leadership with a market
share of 11.3
the company increased its proportion of
cv mix to 24.5
the electric vehicle segment continues
to be a focus area for the company the
company continues to maintain its
leadership position in this segment as
well uh with an estimated market share
of 14
for private cars and 64 in two wheelers
our investment in retail health has
resulted in our agency channel premium
growing up by 18.53
18.3 this quarter
as indicated in our previous calls we
continue with our investment in adding
uh managers to our to grow our retail
health agency business and our current
head count stands which includes new
hires at 1101
we expect the growth to accelerate in
the next few quarters as the agency
managers start getting productive
i would also like to share that our
one-stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs the aisle take care app
has surpassed 1.7 1.7 million users user
downloads till date the incremental
download for the quarter was
0.4 million
our bank issuance and key relationship
groups grew at 49.4 percent this quarter
within this the icc bank distribution
grew a third by 30.5 percent and the
non-ica ban distribution grew by 65.1
percent
post pandemic the recovery and credit
growth along with the increase in wallet
share
in distribution partners acquired
through the de-merchant has been the key
growth driver for us our business source
to our digital one team grew by thirty
point seven percent within that the
business on our website grew by twenty
one point one percent and business
social strategic alliance partners in
the digital ecosystem grew by 170.8
percent overall our digital focus has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues to two point one billion uh
rupees which accounts for three point
nine percent of our overall gdp for this
quarter
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robots growth
driven by 18.7 growth in the sme segment
we are optimistic with the recent
positive regulatory developments uh you
know would enable us to grow faster with
emerging market needs
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as rendering our
distribution engine digital enhancements
uh realizing synergy rationalizing cost
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business i will now request gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the recently concluded quarter
thanks father and uh good evening to
each one of you i will now give you a
brief overview on this of the financial
performance of the company for quarter
one fbi 2023
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
garage direct premium income gdp of the
company was rupees 53.7 billion in
quarter one five twenty three as against
rupees forty one point eight eight
billion in quarter one five twenty two
the growth of twenty eight point two
percent this growth was higher than the
industry growth of 23
our gdpi growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpr grew by 10.3
percent at risk 11.43 billion in quarter
one fbi 23 as against rupees 10.36
billion in quarter one fbi 2022
as indicated in our reserve presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment grew by fourteen point
three percent at which is nineteen point
five four billion in q1 fi twenty three
as again should be seventeen point zero
nine billion in quarter one f by twenty
twenty two
on the retail side of the business gdp
of the motor segment was rupees 17.82
billion in quarter one five twenty three
as against rupees fourteen point zero
one billion in quarter one five twenty
two registering a growth of twenty seven
point two percent
our agent including the point of sale
distribution increased to ninety four
thousand five fifty nine
as on june 30 2022 up from 88 545 as on
march 31 2022
advanced premium numbers was rupees
34.71 billion as at june 30 2022 as
against rupees 33.68 billion as at mass
31 2022.
resultantly the combined issue was 104.1
percent in quarter one fy 23 as against
123.5 percent in quarter one fbi 2022
our investment assets rose to rupees
398.2 billion as at june 30 2022
from rupees 387.86 billion as at march
31 2022.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.18 times as at june 30
compared to 4.23 times as at mars 31
investment income was 26.55 billion in
quarter one fi 23 as again surprise 8.89
billion in 41 fbi 22.
our capital gain was lower at it is
point three two billion
in quarter one five twenty three as
against
three point two seven billion in quarter
one fbi 2022
our profit before tax grew by eighty
percent eighty point one percent that
would be four point six five billion in
quarter one five twenty three as against
rupees two point five eight billion in
quarter one by twenty twenty two
consequently profit after tax grew by
seventy nine point six percent at risk
three point four nine billion in quarter
one five twenty three as the gains
raised one point nine four billion in
quarter one last year
return on average equity was fifteen
percent in quarter one f by twenty three
as against nine point four percent in
quarter one fbi 2022
solvency ratio was 2.61 times as at june
30 2022 as against 2.46 times as at mars
31 2022
continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times
on the ehg front we have voluntarily
adopted the business responsibility and
sustainability reporting for fy 2022
thereby strengthening our commitment to
transparency and disclosures and also to
promote a culture that embraces
sustainability practices within our
business processes the company for the
first time has also disclosed its gsg
emission an independent external
assurance provider has also provided
limited limited assurance on the gh ghg
emission accounting
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth
questionable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times i would like to thank you
all for attending this earnings call and
we will be happy to take any questions
that you may have
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question
maybe star in one on their touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you might press star into
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
participants you may press star in one
to ask a question
[Applause]
the first question is from the line of
deepika mundra from jp morgan please go
ahead
did they become a requested and use your
line from your side with the question
please
hello can you hear
i'll try again hello can you help me yes
much yeah much better yeah okay thanks
uh some trouble with the handset uh okay
uh so on the motor insurance piece um in
terms of
what are you seeing in on claim
inflation uh versus the pricing trend
both on od and tp i think on tp you
already very clearly mentioned you're
running below what the inflationary
trends are so and overall how do you
expect this to impact the combined ratio
this year uh given the fact that the
volumes are on the uptick
uh so if i look at the uh
the ob side uh what we are seeing is a
slightly higher claims frequency than
uh what we had last year
some of it was anticipated you know as
utilization of vehicles is increased but
overall even beyond that
we are seeing slightly higher
uh frequency numbers now normally you
know if you look at the acs it's kind of
you know flat we are not seeing any
significant increase in average claim
size
uh overall in terms of the pricing the
industry has also connected the pricing
little bit on the od side in line with
what we discussed last time but on
balance on the od the price the pressure
on loss ratio uh remains uh in line with
what we've been saying uh over the last
few quarters
on the pp side yes while the premium the
rate increase is not in line with the
same's inflation
thing that we are uh you know hoping to
see uh come through is now that the
motor vehicle rules have been uh framed
we will see how the courts begin to
adopt this you know the six month limit
and the uh the the process the
intubation process
if that you know comes through that
would be a positive uh so that is in a
sense uh you know something that we will
watch very closely for the next two
quarters to get a sense of whether it's
getting implemented if it gets
implemented implemented that will be a
positive overall on the tv side
understood sir and all the new products
which are you know data driven uh this
one can be largely disinflationary in
nature so wouldn't it cap premium growth
to a certain extent or do you see the
penetration benefits of you know
outweighing that significantly
so what
you know it could be a you know mix of
books you're absolutely right so if you
price the exposure which is uh you know
in essence people who drive less and
those are the customers who end up
buying the telematic driven products
that could be uh you know
this is stationary but
what it does is basically price the risk
better and logically the rest of the
book the pricing should go up if that
does not happen then what you're you
know saying may happen we will have to
see how big the penetration of this
piece is because it's just early days
our senses will take fair amount of time
for this to become a large part of the
motor business
the second opportunity that we believe
is there is that you know there is a
large amount of business which is you
know people buying only tp which
potentially can buy od also so if we can
increase penetration that will help
uh understood here um and on our last
one if i may uh in terms of the
quarterly numbers uh
despite the scale up in volume there
seems to be no operating leverage uh
could you uh talk about the investments
i think that you're making on
distribution or anything else that is
contributing to that
yeah so deepika i think what we have
spoken about is
continuing to make those investments in
uh health agency
uh digital and claim service so that's
something that is the continuing one
which is why if you recollect i think
while we are now starting to add almost
close to a thousand health agency
managers which we had spoken about last
year
effectively by end of march we
downloaded about 750 of them
that number if you speak including the
new highest as that june 30 stands at
almost about 100 uh an odd uh
so we are continuing to make those
investments in health agency
distribution
even digital for the matter of fact
again when you look at the numbers which
is growth delivered through both our
contributions coming in from website as
well as the alliance partners startups
that we have
that numbers again has done quite well
uh i mean which was put out even as a
part of our opening remarks that growth
for us has been almost about 30
so that's an area where we are
continuing to make um investments in uh
increasing the sourcing of the digital
channel as well in the third area which
will always continue to stay focused on
is with respect to excellence in claim
service
so those areas are continuing to kind of
stay invested which is why when you look
at the aggregate let's say the growth in
the management expense numbers uh the
overall growth for us for the quarter
one this year has been roughly at about
or maybe on a gross written premium
basis it will be close to about 30
percent basically that if you see the
growth in management expenses has been
about 28
so in some sense there is some element
of operating leverage but at the same
time obviously there are those
continuing investments that we are
making which will obviously play through
as we speak over the next several
quarters
okay so thank you so much i'll get back
in the queue
thank you
next question is from the man of hide
from high tongue please go ahead
yeah thank you for giving me the
opportunity so firstly on the health
segment we are seeing some slow down for
the industry in the retail health what
are your thoughts on that and also if
you could comment on what we are doing
in the health segment exactly for
instance in the icf bank channel we are
highlighted that they have started
selling some amount of indemnity
products so what is the progress there
what is the progress in the other hfc
and bfcs who we wanted to do more
benefit products there
in general indemnity benefit some flavor
on that side i'll follow up with one
more question after that
yeah so uh you know in terms of what
we're doing in health uh you know one is
your first question of these bit of
slowdown there is a bit of base effect
for the industry uh last year's q1 was
very strong so for the industries retail
health growth has got a bit muted but
for us the growth is uh beginning to
pick up uh as we explain the agency
driven business has grown by about 18
for us this quarter
even as the full distribution that we
are ramping up is getting productive so
we believe that this growth for us will
actually increase uh you know going
ahead so from all perspectives as a
positive the second thing is the on the
bank issue inside uh if you look at the
point that i made in my opening remarks
you know the question on ics bank uh as
i explained and we have talked about
this last quarter as well that last year
was a bit of a headwind because the
benefit business that that was sold as
an attachment by the bank
that had uh you know gone away but the
bank had started selling indemnity
products
as a group in a group format as an
attachment to the moderate goals and
that's driving the 30 percent growth in
that channel that we are seeing
the other krg partners in other partners
which is basically the
new uh you know the interesting
relationship that we've had over the
years the nbscs hfcs and other banks
as also the new bank issuance tie-ups
that we've got through the merger with
the barclays
that channel has gone grown really well
and that number that growth is roughly
about 65
so overall the bank is business has
grown by about you know roughly about 50
percent 49.4 percent
split
into 30.5 at the bank level and 65
percent at the other bank assurance
partners
so overall we are and within that the
benefit number is also flown very well
because a lot of the attachment products
that just get sold
by the hfcs and some of the other banks
is a benefit product
so that's what what is growing the group
other segment within health right this
is the
group number yes absolutely right
and so just on the crop segment we have
i think one of you tenders here so we
are again looking to grow crop right
this is in addition to what we got from
bharti exam because our reinsurance
rates also look higher this quarter is
that correct
no that is not correct so what we are
doing is we are kind of so if you look
at what we got from uh
they had two states one was karnataka
the other one was maharashtra
uh maharashtra
changed the scheme from the original
insurance scheme as per pmap to a scheme
where the loss range is capped so it's a
80 to 110 scheme
where if the loss ratio is below 80
as an insurance company we will refund
that premium to the state at the same
time the loss ratio is more than 110
the state will pay for that claim so
it's a it's a you know fixed range
product
which uh you know that's a that's a
replacement of the traditional pms right
so what we've done is in maharashtra in
the in the under the new scheme we've
taken two clusters
uh so aggregate crop numbers for us will
not be very different from what it was
last year maybe marginally you know a
little bit here and there but aggregate
numbers very similar to last year the
reason why we you know big for
maharashtra is because we have kind of
indicated that we will observe how the
scheme
evolves and apparently will take a fall
with the 80 210 model our reinsurance
cost for the stop loss at least to buy
goes away that's a big saving if you
remember we
used to talk about the fact that the
insurance cost is very high for a team
of this nature and that's one of the
reason why we stopped writing this so
that reinsurance cost goes away because
the loss is kept at 110
and you know overall we don't want to
increase the profit exposure beyond the
certain level so you're staying in line
with what we did last year in aggregate
as a company now there's been some
booking difference this year someone
that got booked in the first quarter uh
last year a lot of them got booked in
the second quarter so there may be some
timing differences but aggregate for the
year we don't see uh too much of a
difference in aggregate processes that
we would like
right and just one last thing on motor
od some increase in claim ratio is due
to higher cv business right and this
combined will still be lower is that
understanding correct
so it is what we are kind of indicated
even if you recollect in our earlier
calls we had said particularly on motor
we would look at certain segments which
are which could be relatively high on lr
but could be let's say relatively lower
in so far as 7 cost of distribution is
concerned because from an roe
perspective those kind of distance
selections
makes viable sense so that's one reason
why you also see
maybe an increase in the
od loss ratios and even if you recollect
when we had kind of announced numbers
for the full year at that point of time
we had we did indicate particularly for
let's say on damage maybe quarter four
will be more representative of let's say
what one could experience in so far as
od loss ratios are concerned and so far
as trend line is concerned but having
said that i think the way to look at the
ode uh segment will be to obviously look
at both
the loss ratios first the cost of
distribution is put together and on that
basis is how we are looking at selecting
the portfolio so you could see some
periods where
you would see possibly an increase in
the od loss issues given the fact that
we would want to select certain segments
which could be high on loss ratios in
which case
you may see periods of increasing loss
ratios at the same time possibly we will
see a
moderation in the overall cost of
distribution on an aggregate basis i
think we would want to kind of stay
disciplined in terms of the risk
selection that we do
sure thank you so that's it
thank you
next question is from the line of praise
chain from others one please
yeah hi sir uh a few questions from my
side firstly
uh no we didn't explain in the previous
session
retention ratio visibly the full
financial year
and the quarter one of this year then
obviously it will not be like to like
comparison because
a large part of quarter one business is
largely driven by the commercial line of
uh businesses so particularly let's say
fire engine and bulk of the corporates
they will kind of have their referrals
coming through in quarter one of this
year where relatively because of the
size of the risk is
bigger you tend to have an element of
respiration
it's more towards i would say quarter
three and quarter four where bulk of the
retail business particularly motor and
health will largely get driven and
booked
in so far as business group is concerned
where as we have explained earlier both
on motor and health we kind of live
aside the obligatory minimum which now
for the current year is about four
percent by and large we tend to retain
rest of the risk on the net account
so hence uh whatever retention that you
are seeing of the sixty-five percent
number for quarter one vis-a-vis maybe a
seventy seventy or 72 percent for the
full year may not be a like to like
comparison uh as i said because of the
corporate renewals that happened in the
first quarter
okay got that
uh secondly was on the investment field
so you know it seems to have dropped
sequentially quite a bit uh any
explanation for that
could you just repeat that
so the investment yield on the if i
calculate on the investment book that
seems to have dropped sequentially
materially in this quarter any reason
for that
largely driven by capital gains stock if
you look at the q1 of last year we had
almost 300 crores of capital gains
this quarter that capital gain number is
down to about 35
so that contains q1q
q4
compared to q4
so i'm comparing q1 to q1 q1 last year
we had about 327 crores of capital gains
uh that we had on the investment book
this quarter is about 31 32
if you compare sequentially last quarter
that is q4 of last year we had about 136
close of capital gains
this quarter we have about 32. so even
sequentially dropped a lot it's largely
true with the market context
and these are times you know as a
long-term investors we see these markets
as opportunities to invest rather than
worry about the fact that for this
quarter we've had our capital gains from
okay got that got that and last and
uh could you give an explanation again
possibly now this is a nap to n uh these
and wp ratio
will never assume that in this quarter
there should be an unwind that would
happen from q4
and that
and wp ratio should be a positive number
but
it should be a greater than one number
but anything that you can guide help me
understand that
so nothing specific uh iteration so far
as recognition of earnings is concerned
pretty much it remains the same which is
where which is earnings get uh earned
over the policy contract
what you see as the gap between let's
say growth in let's say premiums or nwp
and nap is largely a function of
the growth coming back in this quarter
which will possibly start seeing
unwinding happening towards the next two
or three quarters
so it's more a catch-up of the growth
that we see coming back in this quarter
visibly let's say you would have looked
at q1 last year for example
the growth for us was low single digit
number
uh in terms of agricultural revenue so
visibly that if you see for quarter one
this year as we expand as a part of the
opening remarks we had a growth in gdp
of almost about 28
so this unwinding of earnings or maybe
the gap that you will see between nap
and nwp will start getting to convert
maybe over the next several quarters of
course
subject to what we get to experience in
so far as growth in
revenue subconscious
all right thank you so much all right
thank you the next question is from the
line of madhukha from illara capital
please go ahead
uh hi uh good evening and thank you for
taking my question most of my questions
have been answered but
uh what's happening on the commission
line so i see like a
drop in the commission ratio
uh what explains that uh i'm guessing
it's something
on the insurance that you would have
earned some commission
uh that's one thing and again the uh
management uh expenses
that have also gone up
uh a lot so so i'm talking not uh not
the insurance related uh expenses but
the expense of management
that's gone up to about 19.8 crore so uh
why is that happening
so i think on the first one
i think in so far as
commissions are concerned yes you are
absolutely right when you look at the
net commission ratio it's a function of
both
what commissions that we pay at the cost
of
doing business
and obviously the element of reinsurance
commission that we earn as a part of
reinsurance reading that we do to the
reinsurers
as we have been explaining particularly
on the reinsurance side
given the outcome that we have exhibited
to the reinsurers we talked about even
in the last quarter to say that
the reinsurance programs that we have
been able to renew for fi 23 has got two
positive changes one is we have been
able to strengthen the panel of
reinsurance which we have been able to
operate with that's positive from a
credit risk standpoint given that we are
working with high quality rangers
the second aspect that we kind of
exhibited also was given the fact that
as i said we have been able to exhibit a
positive outcome to the rangers the
terms of commissions that we have been
able to get from the rangers have also
been relatively better than what we had
seen for fi 22.
so and and as i said
quarter one typically forms
bulk of the corporate policy renewal
cycle
and then to that extent you will always
find in quarter one the extent of
reinsurance commissions coming to you
at the time when the businesses are
booked
and that's the reason why you see
possibly that commission ratios
reflecting a relatively lower number
than what we had seen in the earlier
period so that's in response to the
commission ratio point that you made
on the management expenses as i
explained i think if you look at it this
will be the closing revenues that we
have had
as i said whether either if you look at
it on a gdpi basis or even if you look
at it from a gwp standpoint
we have seen a growth in revenues of
almost about 28 or 30 whichever way you
look at it
visibly that i think if you look at the
growth in management expenses which
includes both
commissions that we incur for cost of
distribution plus let's say the
operating expenses that we incur both of
them put together has grown by grown at
about 27.8
uh so hence i think whatever
increase in numbers that you are seeing
is relative to the
growth in revenues that one has seen at
the same time i think we are as what we
have been explaining we continue to see
let's say relative
competitive intensity continuing in the
market and hence to that extent that's
also a factor that is playing to with
respect to the management access number
got it so this uh commission ratio part
of it uh you know should is it more like
a quarter one phenomena or do you think
it will normal normalized during the
yesterday or i'm guessing some some
portion of it
there should be some uh further
reduction in in the balance
uh
i don't know what does that mean
yeah i don't mean on a quarter of i mean
i don't mean from the 2.2 percent that
they're seeing right now but uh on a
year-over-year basis there should be
some reduction because of what you
mentioned right now
that's right so again it's a function of
how do we see let's say growth coming
back i think while quarter one has been
good let's say from even from a to
summation from a retail standpoint so
that obviously involves an element of uh
commissions expenses that will have to
incur for doing the business so over the
next three quarters we will have to see
how that growth momentum plays out which
will also have a factor in terms of
the commission ratio numbers
to over the next three quarters
definitely you will see the extent of
reinsurance commissions that we would
have earned in quarter one that number
we definitely see a
relatively declining number as we move
towards quarter two quarter three and
quarter four given the fact as i said
and maybe q2 and q3 q4 also to some
extent the cycle comes back in terms of
reinsurance commissions because
some of the companies which follow a
january to december cycle they will have
their renewal period starting from
january 1. so there again you will see
an element of
reinsurance commission that will play
out so there are multiple factors that
get attached to this number so obviously
we will have to wait and see how the
growth plays out on the retail side
and equally
as i said in terms of the renewal cycle
that will happen in q4 will also be a
factor that will drive the insurance
commission this
and any particular license
i will request you to come back in the
question queue for a follow-up question
sure thank you
the next question is from the land of
avinash singh from mk global please go
ahead
yeah hi
uh
uh so first question is uh more problem
you know thank you perspective i mean
you are well capitalized over
capitalized and commercial lines
typically
you have your sort of i would say
strength as well
uh so i mean how is the pricing
environment because i see in commercial
line you are more or less maintaining
your market share to slightly feeding in
some lines so i mean uh why not
certainly because you have advantage on
the reason side as well you have
possible your capital rate why not
shorter for a bit aggressive on you know
commercial line especially in the
backdrop when the retail lines uh are
seeing uh height and contribution all i
mean
ongoing so that's one then i will come
up with a follow-up question
oh that's a good great question avinash
and if you see the last three or four
years we've consistently gained on the
commercial segment our expectation that
is that even this year we will gain
it is just that uh in the month we
always find that the because the big
month for commercial business most
companies renew
uh there is a lot of uh pricing uh
aggression that happened
just in that month uh and we are usually
a bit more cautious in that month and
then gain during the rest of the year so
our anticipation is that even this year
like in the last three four years we'll
gain uh
on the commercial lines of business uh
also uh one of the point that we made is
the sme business for us has been growing
we are
even more uh you know sustaining that
effort in the emerging markets of the
you know more more you know more in the
you know more
distributed markets of the country and
we hope to see some traction there so
your point is absolutely right and
that's what our plan is we hope to
increase our commercialized market share
even this year like the last few years
i would say uh indicating
uh
i mean the first capital continues to
pour in
and when sector profitability is some of
the metrics you know and we see
initials are not very impressive so i
you know
i think you asked a question about new
capital coming in is that the question
yeah i'm trying to check here capital
continue to change i mean uh you know
and grow up in this sector when the
pricing basically already not coming
back i mean how long this you know of uh
i would say the worst pricing cycle
particularly in the worker or d to
continue i mean i mean regulator of
course i know meter has given you a
benign height but lemonade cannot be
giving a hike
in
yeah so i think that's again you know
good question avinash so and you're
absolutely right you cannot seek too
much of an increase in tp if we don't
see disciplinary od beyond the point uh
though honestly speaking when you look
at uh you know each segment of risks
each risk should be appropriately priced
that's the uh you know that's the
ultimate principle but having said that
your larger question about when we see
discipline on the od side i think this
quarter we've seen some uh you know some
discipline coming in terms of uh you
know some rationalization by a few
players not all
but i think the larger issue is that if
more capital comes into a sector there
will always be uh you know
aggressive behavior by some players and
unfortunately a lot of investors
mistakenly believe that the valuation of
a company is a price to gw's multiple
which actually makes no sense
uh hopefully given the
change in the overall uh you know macro
environment for for you know more
sensible uh you know
investment valuations we will see some
of those changes
uh but you know till that happens there
will be some that pressure so i mean
we've always been saying that you know
motorola normally rationalizes very you
know within about a year and a half so
we had we expected to happen this year
but we'll have to watch for it i mean
the first quarter was small signs in
that direction
at the same time as i said unfortunately
the claims frequency was a bit more than
what i guess the industry anticipated so
on balance that that cancelled each
other out but we'll have to see how that
you know goes ahead for the next uh you
know next three quarters
thank you
avinash i'll request to come back in the
question queue for a follow-up question
thank you
the next question is from the line of
rishi jinjinwala from ifl institutional
equities please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity a couple
of questions from my side uh firstly on
on the motor tp i guess the has the rate
height being effective from first june
and uh if that were to be the case then
uh you know in the quarterly motor tp
loss ratio um given the price hike will
come true fully into queue if everything
else remains similar we should expect
improvement there going forward right
we should tp loss issues as we've always
been saying look at on an annual basis
don't look at a quarterly basis because
there are you know and in fact last year
end of the year also we had indicated
that look at the annual uh you know rate
for you know our annual loss ratio rate
for pp uh because there could be
quarters based on the actual model there
could be releases for that quarter there
could be you know in another quarter
they may not be released so uh our
recommendation has has always been to
look at pp loss ratio at an annual basis
rather than a quarterly basis
okay and and the other thing is can you
give us some sense of how much of our
motor book currently would be coming
from uh
new vehicle sales and and how much would
be
uh on the motor tv site from long-term
tp
so rishi for the first quarter uh the
business mix in terms of new and renewal
uh is about 40 60 40 of the business is
new 60 of the business is renewal
and this number if you look at for
quarter one last year that number was
about 35 percent was new and the balance
65 percent was renewable for the full
year pretty much it was similar we are
almost about one-third roughly about 33
which was new and the rest was uh
renewable
and within motor tp the long term tp
portion would be
we don't have that number separately
kind of put out but
i would say that i think the advanced
premium numbers is what we kind of put
out i think if you look at that number
for the uh quarter ended june 30 is
roughly at about
34.7 billion
this number at the end of march 32 over
33.
almost about 100 higher than what we had
towards the end of last year
okay all right thank you
thank you
a request to all the participants please
restrict to two questions for
participants if time permit please come
back in the question q for a follow-up
question
the next question is from the line of
nadesh from investec please go ahead
uh control the opportunity for this
question firstly on the health
challenge the data which insurance in uh
council where we have not been able to
uh make any impact despite hiring so
many people in last 12 months
uh our market share has not changed
uh uh so any comment on that that is one
second is
if i look at uh claims uh experience
data of fi-22 uh our claim regulation
ratio claim resolution as percentage of
claims estimated in health insurance
insurance around 20
uh which is similar to other companies
so how do we think about customer
experience uh on the hundreds because i
think last year a lot of companies a lot
of customers had a pretty bad experience
with respect to health insurance
settlement across the sector
so in that scenario how are we
differentiating ourselves uh our
respective customers at customer
experience
so narration the first one as we
indicated so our retail health numbers
had businesses that we were sourcing
from retail agency channel as also some
businesses that we are selling through
banks uh you know as a retail health
business so if you look at the agency
channel
the number that we gave out we grew at
about 18
for this quarter uh our sense is given
that you know these you know agency
managers agents are getting more used to
our systems processes and getting more
productive that number this quarter
should uh you know should we should be
able to deliver higher growth in this
quarter
the aggregate number for retail health
was a bit lower because
uh one of the banks which was selling
things as a retail policy has converted
that business to a group format so it's
kind of shifted from retail health to a
group health but underlying businesses
you know b2b2c customer base uh
but as i said the retail health channels
that we are investing in go at about 18
we expect the number to go uh higher in
this quarter uh coming back to your
question on uh you know the claims
experience you're right for some
companies this was an issue last year
and i believe
the regulator actually asked them to
reopen their claims and pay more
subsequently
that happened for a few companies not
for us
we had paid whatever we believe was
relevant and that was fine with uh you
know in in that sense uh i think the
approach that we've taken is that uh you
know the entire journey of claims has to
be uh
you know as much as possible on our
intake care app to you know increase
engagement and uh you know service
experience what we are seeing is
increasingly the cashless is always you
know directly done uh you know to us but
even reimbursement claims with uh that's
a corporates we are seeing almost 50
percent of the reimbursement claim
coming through the app now and we
believe your service experience is
significantly superior
uh you know and and that's been the
approach that we've taken in terms of
the claims experience
what we also
watch is the number of complaints uh of
customers
and we track all complaints on whether
they we refute the claim do the customer
goes to an ombudsman and when it goes to
an ombudsman or a court what is our
winning ratio so we track all you know
claims which we deny for what we believe
are valid reasons uh you know what do
they do we end up losing those cases in
the court so we track all losses to till
the end that end and our experience and
all of that has been you know quite
positive our wind loss ratio in the
legal court and ombudsman is very high
sure
one follow up on motor insurance
uh is it reasonable it is
share in the new vehicle while probably
we have been gaining market share on the
new one book uh given given the changing
strategy which we articulated last
quarter
to some extent yes i mean if you look at
our new market share is lower than what
we were last year while gopal gave you
the mix because overall new vehicle
sales has been higher uh given the
strategy that we articulated uh you know
given the overall cost of the function
in some of these channels we are kind of
you know we're kind of calibrating the
book and our sharing new has come around
a little bit in private card that is but
in cv we've gained in two weeks largely
held up
this was in line with what we uh talked
about in april
yeah
thank you
a request to all the participants please
restrict to two questions per
participant
the next question is from the line of
the punjab from city
insurance policies uh
earlier uh you know historically we have
seen for both lombard and the industry
the case which should be on the higher
side and probably the pricing on the
large corporate things significantly
higher than the sme sites so just look
make some sense of how things are uh
kind of uh turning out in that section
how the pricing is and how our election
is this has been uh changes within that
overall uh book out there
uh i think one of the changes that we
are seeing on the group health side is
we are seeing at least with some of the
uh players we are seeing a bit more
discipline coming in obviously last
year's losses have hurt the industry we
are seeing some discipline coming in one
of the things that we have talked about
last year from from the july uh you know
uh quarter onwards we had talked about
the fact that we
had been increasing uh you know premium
per life by about 15
uh but we have seen cutting uh you know
retention of our of our customers given
our service you know uh you know
proposition that we had that story
continues even this year we are seeing a
person premium uh you know premium per
life premium increase
uh which should help in terms of the
loss ratios
the other point to keep in mind is uh
you know in group health the cost of
distribution is very minimal
particularly for us because we do a lot
of business directly
so overall combined even if the loss
ratio is in the you know low 90s the
combined works out well for us
and just to follow up on that it's very
metric that you track on you know how
much of those customers have you been
able to cross sell or is that even a
focus area
it is a focus area so if you look at the
uh approach to crosstalk was largely
triggered by the i'll take care app that
we talked about two years back uh so
what we are seeing is that
almost close to 50 of the
employees of our corporates are
downloading the app
and that number is increasing quarter
and quarter we are seeing them using the
app and i gave the point the data about
them filing reimbursement claims through
the app and our thought processes as you
get more engagement you will then look
at you know cross-selling and you know
it's only last year that we started
the sales process on that app
the sales numbers on a month on month
basis is you know is uh growing quite
well
if you look at the uh
the uh the growth in the uh i'll take
your app download i'll give you numbers
from q2 to q3 to q4 to
you know q1 this year on the group uh
you know segment
in q2 last year about 38 percent of our
employees in the group uh you know
employees of groups that we had insured
they would have taken i taken the i'll
take care of download that number has
moved over 48
and i gave the number in terms of the
usage of those apps
the sales and the cost sales numbers are
picking up month on month
as we speak for this month
the total sales on that app is
roughly about uh
wasn't there
oh backwards thanks
thank you
next question is from the line of shreya
shavani from clsa india please go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity so i
have two questions first i think i
missed your explanation on why the lost
ratios in crop
are surprisingly better like 63 versus
historically we've always seen like a
100 plus percent ratio first is that and
second uh um it's a bit more technical
here but i just wanted to get a clarity
on the um the unexpired risk reserve so
for fy 22 the unexpired risk reserve
also includes an adjustment for the um
merger the impact of the merger around
10 10 billion on that 80 billion of url
that you have
so when i but but
in the pnl that adjustment doesn't flow
in the pnl where you have between the
net uh earned premium and net written
premium there the change in reserve uh
change in urr doesn't include that
impact uh
so
just wanted to understand in bharti axa
how is the reserving methodology is it
different from ics or lombard and then
should i when i build my future numbers
should i uh take the reserving how
should i take the reserving going ahead
like uh right now your ur is at around
59 to 60 percent of your net gross
premiums how would it be going ahead
will it largely be the same or any way
parking access is not a very big
chunk of the gross feelings but uh just
some clarity on that
one
uh the second question first
i think as i kind of explained so far as
the unexpected reserve is concerned it's
purely a function of earning the
premiums over the policy contract
so that is pretty much
similar whether it is for icc number or
whether it is for the incoming company
bharti exam so hence to that extent
there is no
difference in methodology or approaches
in which earnings were done by both the
company
second
in terms of for you to model what is it
that the ur could be as a percentage of
net premium honestly very difficult for
me to kind of give you a number for the
simple reason as i said
if you look at for example this
particular quarter which was in response
to one of the other questions the growth
in revenues for us was almost close to
28 29 the growth in earned premium
because i mean maybe the change in
earned money was only about 10
that's primarily because as we said
quarter one last year growth was
relatively muted growth has come back to
us in q1 this year so obviously you will
see let's say a relatively relative
lower contribution of earned premium
coming in from the policies that we have
written in the last year
and the ones that we have written on an
incremental growth in quarter one of
this year will start to play out as we
speak
which i mentioned over the next three or
four quarters
so so that's one and second also is i
mean over the next three quarters for
the year it depends on what kind of
growth that we are able to exhibit
in terms of distances from different
segments
that will also be a function of
how the url as a percentage of net
premium could kind of play out so very
difficult to give a point number
but as i said it's nothing but
just earning of the premiums over the
contract period
predominantly i would say a large part
of our contracts are annual in nature i
mean barring some of the
long-term policies that we may issue
which is not a very large proportion of
our
overall numbers
but given the fact that a large majority
of the policies that we are writing are
annual contracts i think to that
actually depends on at what point of
time we see growth getting exhibited and
the earnings will happen corresponding
to these therefore a better thing to
look for will be more maybe which is
what we keep saying i think look at it
more from an absolute a final
underwriting outcome in terms of the
combined ratios or maybe the loss ratios
which is kind of factors in both
the element of earnings that has been
done for the risk that has been
underwritten and corresponding to that
particular risk which has been earned
what has been the claim experience
therefore i think that could be a better
measure to kind of look for across
different segments rather than just
looking at only unexpected
risk discover
on an
independent basis so that's one in
response to your
unexpected reserve question
on the first question of yours in terms
of why crop portfolio has exhibited a
relatively lower
loss ratios as we keep saying
generally quarters will always have
operations in different lines of
businesses in terms of lost experiences
and in the past if you recollect the
approach that we have followed
particularly on crop has been that we
obviously given the fact that we don't
have complete information on the claim
position
we tend to reserve conservatively on a
no profit no loss basis however
factoring it for the cost of
reinsurance protection that we take as
and when maybe you have evidences of
claim getting factored in appropriately
in terms of loss experience we tend to
kind of actualize those numbers so yes
to that section you will always find in
let's say in some quarters when the
claim experiences are getting actualized
you will possibly see a loss ratios
which is relatively lower than what you
would have seen
at the time when we estimated the loss
experience so which is why in q1 you see
possibly the loss ratios on crop at
maybe at about 65
but secondly i think when you look at
the crop earned premium for this quarter
is just about eight nine crores
so hence uh from an absolute number
standpoint it does not have a material
impact to the overall
numbers for the quarter
so principally the the
had written while we had provided higher
earlier in reality is looking like a
better book than what we had provided
for
but the impact internal aggregate pnl is
not material
thank you sure i'll requested to come
back in the question q for a follow-up
question
thank you
the next question is from the land of
prakhar sharma from jefferies india
please go ahead
thank you
so
just a broader level question in terms
of you know the uh direction of uh
you know combined ratio and return on
equity uh you know with the uh you know
acquisition of parties
had you know identified some areas where
you can have some cost efficiencies etc
so uh over next
two years or so
what in your view will be the direction
of
uh these two line items uh and uh you
know what could be the critical
assumption that you are building in to
towards improving you know return on
equity from about fifteen percent which
used to be plus twenty percent uh and
within that the combined ratio which you
know uh fi 21 was a good year and 99 100
percent but now we are at 104. so if you
could just give some direction over the
next two years where should we be
expecting
thank you
so far in line with what we said uh you
know
simply because of the merger we would
have ended up with 100 405 we saw the
synergy benefits of roughly 200 cores
that we anticipate for this year we said
we will reinvest that back and hence we
had said at the beginning of this year
that our combined ratio will be elevated
above our normal 101 number that we had
over the last few years
elevated means it will be in this
ballpark that you're seeing now you know
and over the next two years we hope to
bring it down gradually we don't expect
the number to go below 100 in this
two-year period but the trend line would
be you know gradual reduction
at the same time the focus for us as
we've been saying is that you know you
know we want to continue to grow some of
these businesses where we are investing
particularly in health and and digital
and some of the other areas in the
technology side that we are investing
that is something that we want to
continue to focus on
what it translates to and you know
because health business is relatively
lower are we than than you know
corporate business it translates to uh
are we number which is in the high teens
that's what we think we will be able to
deliver over the next up over these
periods over the next two
years thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sanket goda from spark capital advisors
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the
so opportunity
have two questions one one one if you
can give the breakup of health loss
ratio broken down into
health retail health and ca uh so so
just wanted to understand uh which
segments about the increment in the loss
issues compared to the previous contract
and second question was with respect to
the commercial vehicles we had a year in
target to achieve around 25 percent of
the total book today to be commercial
vehicles which we seem to be have acute
in the first four results so
how do we see we see
far as the health uh split on the loss
ratios are concerned between
corporate and the retail indemnity book
the corporate loss ratios for the mutual
standards are about 91
and on the retail indemnity book the
loss ratio is about 78 percent
this if you look at wizard we last year
honestly it may not be a relative
comparison because that was the year
where we had those impacts of covet
losses both on
the corporate book as well as on the
retail inventory book but the numbers
what i gave you is for the current
quarter one
of this year
the details health process showed
compared to you must 78 having a newer
contribution to the entire spine uh
because i just wanted to understand uh
uh uh what led to that uh
last year fourth quarter we had some
substitute question kind of elaboration
yeah so
repeating this point
uh quarterly loss ratios has got many
elements attached to it and therefore to
that extent one will not necessarily be
representative of uh
what loss experience is for the book
that we are underwriting
hence to that extent uh comparing a q4
number with let's say q1 of this year
may not be a like to like comparison
i think a better thing will be to start
looking at lost experiences over annual
cycles which will be far more better
reflection of the portfolio that
that one is underwriting so that's one
the second and more important thing is
uh if you recollect even what we had
spoken during our annual earnings call
in april
we did indicate that possibly
particularly in this quarter one
one could possibly see some still
increase in
non-coveted health intimations
that's something we are continuing to
see in this quarter we did exhibit
relatively heightened number of
claim intimations which has happened on
the non-covet health front
the question for us is whether is it
again just bunch of cases which has
happened in quarter one
or is this trend line likely to be more
structural in terms of intimations to
continue in the next few quarters so
we'll wait for a couple of uh maybe a
couple of particularly quarter two we
will observe
how the intimations are happening in so
far as
non-covet health claims are concerned
and to even on the acs front i think we
have seen maybe slight increase in the
average claim sizes relative to what we
have seen in the earlier period that
again is something that we are doing a
watch to see whether is it more
structural or is there
we could possibly see lectin maybe
reduction as we look at in the
subsequent quarters
so these are things that uh we like to
kind of watch out for and maybe we will
be able to come back with a better
estimate of
what direction the loss issues could
take but in so far as the portfolio that
we are underwriting
as we explained i think we are looking
at writing a book
on the retail indemnity side which
from a steady state standpoint both new
plus renewals put together
you would want to see that portfolio
running with a loss ratio in the range
of 65 to 70
got it
uh on the cv question yeah on the cvr we
believe our range will remain in the 20s
we reach over 24
in this quarter but the range will
remain in the 20s that's the plan
but but it will be new net or renewable
net
sorry
uh it will be new business or renewable
people feel like a bit of both we've
gained into the new share also in the cv
side but the larger focus is on the
agency channel so it will be more old
okay
and the last one uh in the office side
on the opex side uh the the sales and
promotion expenditure which is almost
doubled year on year
maybe maybe have declined quarter
quarter
so exactly what is this nature of this
expenditure because because uh jesus
wanted to understand
that we increase that we encourage in
the in connection with sourcing of
businesses
and ensure that action which is why i
think when we look at the numbers we
always look at it more from a management
expense ratio standpoint which is which
includes both
the commissions that we are required to
kind of pay for the cost of doing
business
and at the same time some of the other
operating expenses which we incur in
order to kind of
run the business on a sustainable basis
so there if you look at the map which is
why i gave out that give out that
management expense uh changed or varies
between the quarter one last year and
quarter of this year
that we gave you the growth in revenues
if you see just to kind of repeat our
top line has grown by about 28 29
the management expense growth has been
about 27.8
so that's the way we look at the end of
the day
whether it is commissions or whether it
is let's say operating expenses all of
them go into let's say cost of doing the
business this will also include maybe
some of the investments that we are
doing particularly on the digital side
for example when we are required to do a
lot of marketing and other
related promotional uh efforts
those also gets into the sales promotion
uh related cost
so hence the better way to look at it is
more the expense ratio number which is
the management expense ratio number
rather than looking at
the line item on a standalone date
thank you very much
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
a last question
i will now hand the conference over to
the management for closing comments
well thank you thank you guys for
joining in it's pretty late in the day
uh and we are very happy to take any
questions that you may have subsequently
look forward to you know meeting you
during the course thank you bye thank
you so much
thank you very much
on behalf of icici lombard general
insurance limited that concludes this
conference
thank you for joining us you may now
disconnect your minds thank you thanks